Guide to the William L. Taylor papers, 1954-2009 MS2287
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Subject files, 1954-2003; Series 3; 24.5 Linear Feet
  - General, Series 3 Subseries 8
    - Fort Wayne -- student discipline policies and practices, 1984-1988; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Fort Wayne Housing Authority minutes, 1964-1976; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Fort Wayne Housing Authority minutes, 1977-1987; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - D'Nell v. FWCS [Fort Wayne Community Schools], 1980; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Follins v. FWCS [Fort Wayne Community Schools], 1974; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Payton v. FWCS [Fort Wayne Community Schools], Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Pinkston v. FWCS [Fort Wayne Community Schools], 1976; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Ray v. FWCS [Fort Wayne Community Schools], 1980; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Reed v. FWCS [Fort Wayne Community Schools], 1974; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Stebing v. FWCS [Fort Wayne Community Schools], 1988; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - David Futterman -- Info re: state reports, studies, and cases that we've been trying to track down, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - D.C. Circuit Pro-Bono Committee, 1991-92; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Documents, 1960; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - East Palo Alto Community Law Project, 1997; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Education bill for Senator Muskie [1 of 2], 1970-71; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Education bill for Senator Muskie [2 of 2], 1970-71; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Georgetown University Law Center, 1992; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - GOP education legislation, 1999-2000; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Gray Report: A Report on Educational Opportunities in Selected Montana School Districts, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - Guidelines for Comprehensive Guidance and Counseling Services, New Jersey Department of Education, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Hawkins project -- proposal and contract, 1990; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Hawkins report outline, 1990; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Hawkins project -- clips, 1990; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Hawkins project -- consultation, 1990 September 14; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Hawkins -- draft Ch. 8, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Hawkins project -- data, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Helena Elementary School District v. State, 1989; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Helena v. Montana District Court opinion, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Helena v. Montana District Court opinion, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - HEW List of Districts under Review, 1971; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - High-stakes testing, 2000-2001; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Hillel Academic Associates, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Horton v. Meskill, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Horton v. Meskill (Connecticut), 1985 January 15; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Housing -- 1968 Housing Act, Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - HUD summaries of resolutions [1 of 2], undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - HUD summaries of resolutions [2 of 2], undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Indianapolis school case, 1982-1983; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Joint Economic Committee: Hearing on Education, U.S. Economic Performance, and the Federal Role, Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Judge William Wayne Justice, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Marmur, Mildred [literary agent], 2003; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Memphis police brutality hearings, Taylor, 1970; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - MHRC [Metropolitan Human Rights Commission] monthly report, 1973 January-February; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - MHRC [Metropolitan Human Rights Commission] official ordinances, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - MHRC [Metropolitan Human Rights Commission], 1964-1978; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - MHRC [Metropolitan Human Rights Commission], 1969-1983; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - MHRC [Metropolitan Human Rights Commission], undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - MHRC [Metropolitan Human Rights Commission], undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - MHRC [Metropolitan Human Rights Commission] annual reports, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - MHRC [Metropolitan Human Rights Commission] correspondence, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - MHRC [Metropolitan Human Rights Commission] documents, 1966-1987; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - MHRC [Metropolitan Human Rights Commission] Graham Statement re: Peabody Study, 1975; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - MHRC [Metropolitan Human Rights Commission] minutes, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Minorities in higher education, 1987-1988; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Muskie file, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - National Conference on Constitutional Rights and American Freedom, 1960; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - National service legislation, 1988-1989; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Neas education policy paper, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Neas position papers, 1998; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - OCR [Office of Civil Rights] test guidance, 1999; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Office for Civil Rights, 1991; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Passion of my Times correspondence, Series 3 Subseries (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Passion of my Times events, Series 3 Subseries (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - Passion of my Times reviews, Series 3 Subseries (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - Passion of my Times sales figures, Series 3 Subseries (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - Pauley v. Kelly (West Virginia), undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 19)
    - Perez v. Bell, 1983; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Perkins paper, 1979; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Pertschuk, Michael -- chapter draft, 1985-1986; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - PR Solutions work agreement, Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 94, Folder 12)
    - PRRAC/JNE and Ed. conference, 1998; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - PRRAC Board meeting and JNE Project, 1996 December; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 108, Folder 10)
    - QEM project meeting, 1988 July 15; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Racial Justice Act, 1991; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Jennifer Renne: Kentucky re: Disparities, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Jennifer Renne: Montana re: Disparities, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Jennifer Renne -- school finance draft, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Reports on race and housing, 1964-1965; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Research -- Executive Action Government Contracts Committee, 1960; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Richmond -- Mehrige, 1972; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 110, Folder 13)
    - Robinson v. Cahill (Robinson I) (New Jersey), 1973 April 3; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - Robinson v. Cahill (Robinson II) (New Jersey), 1973 June 19; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Robinson v. Cahill (Robinson III) (New Jersey), 1975 January 23; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - Robinson v. Cahill (Robinson IV) (New Jersey), 1975 May 23; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Robinson v. Cahill (Robinson V) (New Jersey), 1976 January 30; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Robinson v. Cahill (Robinson VI) (New Jersey), 1976 May 13; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 17)
    - Robinson v. Cahill (Robinson VII) (New Jersey), 1976 June 15; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 18)
    - Implementing Robinson v. Cahill -- article by Berke and Sinkin, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Rockefeller/Urban Institute Testing Conference, 1991; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Role of lawyers and legal education in institutional change, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Rolodex, Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 104)
    - Prepared for 9/14 Educ. meeting -- memor for participants re: recent school finance decisions, Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Principles Statement -- Taylor, ADA, 1970; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - School finance [1 of 2], Series 3 Subseries (Box 106, Folder 9)
    - School finance [2 of 2], Series 3 Subseries (Box 106, Folder 10)
    - School finance litigation, 1969; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - South Bend Justice Department settlement, 1990; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - State Advisory Committees, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Study Team Report: "Does Money Make a Difference in the Quality of Education in the Montana Schools", undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Swann v. Charlotte-Mecklenberg, Taylor amicus brief, 1970; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - WLT [William L. Taylor's] proposal for school finance report, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - WLT [William L. Taylor] -- Emerson, Haber, Dorsen -- "Political and Civil Rights in the United States", undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Testing, 2000-2001; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Testimony on the Quality Education Act of 1990 by M. Morheuser, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - unlabeled [Quality Education Act of 1990], undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Title I, 2000; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Title I, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Title I accountability and testing language, 2000 February; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Title I, 1998 September 18; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Title I Commissioner correspondence, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Title I Congress, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Title I Feinstein, 2000 March; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Title I funding, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Title I graphics, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Title I -- Helping Disadvantaged Children Meet High Standards [1 of 2], undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Title I -- Helping Disadvantaged Children Meet High Standards [2 of 2], undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Title I and HHS appropriations, LCCR and other letters, 1999-2000; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Title I in Midstream, 1998; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Title I Jeffords markups, 2000 March; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Title I markups Jeffords Sessions -- hate crimes, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Title I notes, 1998; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Title I -- media packet, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Title I -- media strategies, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Title I -- op-ed, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Title I project proposal, 1997; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Title I Reform Network, 1998; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Title I regulatory issues, 1998; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Title I report drafts, 1998 May; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Title I steering committee, 1997-1998; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Title I testing issues -- Wellstone, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Title I -- Transfer and portability, 1999 November; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - LEP -- Titles I and IV in Senate, 2000 January; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Title V -- teacher training, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Transcript of the hearings on the Fair Chance Act and CRS reports, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - UDC, 1983; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Civil Rights Commission -- Arthur Flemming, 1991; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Valenzuela v. O'Connell, 2006; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Voter registration Senate S. 874, 1989; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Voter registration -- Motor Voter, 1989; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Voting Rights Act of 1965 -- extension, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Washington Committee for NAACP Defense Fund, 1968; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - West Haven schools, 1969; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Parents Involved in Community Schools v. Seattle School District, LCCR amicus brief, undated; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 112, Folder 8)
- Publications, 1948-2009; Series 4; 15 Linear Feet
  Arranged chronologically, with clippings first and other publications second.
  This series contains published books and reports, as well as some draft material, written by Taylor and his colleagues primarily from 1981 through 2009. This series is not yet processed.
  - Clippings, 1958; Series 4 (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Clippings scrapbook, 1965; Series 4 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1960-1969; Series 4 (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Clippings on employment testing, 1968; Series 4 (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1968; Series 4 (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1970; Series 4 (Box 110, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1971; Series 4 (Box 110, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1971-1983; Series 4 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1972-1975; Series 3 Subseries 8 (Box 110, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1970-1979; Series 4 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1973; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1976-77; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1978; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1979; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1979; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1980; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1981; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1982; Series 4 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1983; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, Cincinnati, 1984; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1984; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1985; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1986; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1987-88; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1989; Series 4 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Clippings [1 of 3], 1980-1989; Series 4 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Clippings [2 of 3], 1980-1989; Series 4 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Clippings [3 of 3], 1980-1989; Series 4 (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1991; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1992; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Congressional Record and Bronson material, newsclips, 1993; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - St. Louis clippings, 1995-96; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Clippings [1 of 11], 1990-1999; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Clippings [2 of 11], 1990-1999; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Clippings [3 of 11], 1990-1999; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Clippings [4 of 11], 1990-1999; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Clippings [5 of 11], 1990-1999; Series 4 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Clippings [6 of 11], 1990-1999; Series 4 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Clippings [7 of 11], 1990-1999; Series 4 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Clippings [8 of 11], 1990-1999; Series 4 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Clippings [9 of 11], 1990-1999; Series 4 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Clippings [10 of 11], 1990-1999; Series 4 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Clippings [11 of 11], 1990-1999; Series 4 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 2000; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 2001-2002; Series 4 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 2000-2001; Series 4 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 2002-2007; Series 4 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Article drafts, Brooklyn College, undated; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn College Vanguard, 1948 December-1949 May; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Brooklyn College Vanguard, 1949 September-November; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Brooklyn College Vanguard, 1950 January-May; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn College Kingsman, 1950 October-December; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn College Kingsman, 1951 January-May; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Campus News [Brooklyn College], 1950 October-December; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - College newspapers addressing Brooklyn College Vanguard news, 1950 October; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Brooklyn College, 1950; Series 4 (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - "Legal Action to Enjoin Legislative Malapportionment", 1961; Series 4 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Taylor publications, 1962-68; Series 4 (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Proposals and articles, 1962-68; Series 4 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Book -- Simon and Schuster, 1967; Series 4 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - "Hanging Together" testimonials, undated; Series 4 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - "Hanging Together" reviews Psychology Today, undated; Series 4 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - "Hanging Together" reviews etc., Series 4 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Articles and materials for book ["Hanging Together"], undated; Series 4 (Box 82)
  - Executive Implementation of Federal Civil Rights Law, 1968; Series 4 (Box 82)
  - Articles, 1962-79; Series 4 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Some Thoughts on Political Strategy in the 1970s, undated; Series 4 (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Taylor articles, 1971-72; Series 4 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Taylor articles, 1973; Series 4 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Taylor articles, 1974-75; Series 4 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Taylor articles, 1975-77; Series 4 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Taylor articles, 1977; Series 4 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Taylor articles, 1977; Series 4 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Taylor articles, 1978; Series 4 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Taylor articles, 1979; Series 4 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Taylor articles, 1980-81; Series 4 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Taylor articles, 1981-82; Series 4 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Psychology Today, 1971; Series 4 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Building the Consensus: Civil Rights and the Department of Justice by Rafferty, 1976; Series 4 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Rockefeller affirmative action paper, 1980-82; Series 4 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Without Justice: A Report on the Conduct of the Justice Department in Civil Rights in 1981-82, 1981-1982; Series 4 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Citizen Participation articles, 1981-1986; Series 4 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Dunbar, Les -- Douglas inquiry, 1983; Series 4 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Yale Law Journal, 1986; Series 4 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Shortchanging Children: The Impact of Fiscal Inequity on the Education of Children at Risk, 1990; Series 4 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Kuttner -- The Declining Middle, 1983; Series 4 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Bellagio paper notes, 1983; Series 4 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Taylor articles, 1983-84; Series 4 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Taylor articles, 1984; Series 4 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Taylor articles, 1985-88; Series 4 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Taylor articles, 1990-92; Series 4 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Lost Opportunities -- clippings, undated; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Lost Opportunities -- press file, undated; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - William L. Taylor statement, Lost Opportunities, 1991 April 17; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Members of the Commission, Lost Opportunities, undated; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Comments CCCR/Minority Scholarships, 1991; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Lost Opportunities -- author's list, undated; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - ADA midterm Bush report, undated; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Release of Lost Opportunities Report, 1991; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Lost Opportunities -- press responses, 1991; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Lost Opportunities -- press release, undated; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Original newsclippings of Lost Opportunities, 1991 April; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - Lost Opportunities newsclippings, 1991 April; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 12)
  - Renewal form of R.R. Bowker, 1992; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 13)
  - Microfiche listing -- Lost Opportunities, 1992; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 14)
  - CCCR publications, 1991-92; Series 4 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Lost Opportunities endnotes, undated; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 15)
  - Lost Opportunities responses, undated; Series 4 (Box 87, Folder 16)
  - Thurgood Marshall article, 1993; Series 4 (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - School desegregation article, 1997; Series 4 (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - Taylor articles, 1993-99; Series 4 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Taylor articles, 1993; Series 4 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Taylor articles, 2000-03; Series 4 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Taylor articles, 2003-04; Series 4 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - DOJ Project, 2003; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Appeal letter -- contributions, 2004; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Civil Rights Report, undated; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Administration -- Civil Rights Report, 2006; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - DOJ -- Civil Rights Report, 2006; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Education -- Civil Rights Report, 2006; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Healthcare -- Civil Rights Report, 2006; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Housing -- Civil Rights Report, 2006; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Judiciary -- Civil Rights Report, 2006; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Signing statements -- Civil Rights Report, 2006; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Voting rights -- Civil Rights Report, 2006; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Civil rights articles, 2006; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Testing in Spanish, undated; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Advisory Committee CCCR and NCTQ CBA project, undated; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - CBA project materials, undated; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 15)
  - CBA union correspondence, 2006 October; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 16)
  - CCCR correspondence, 2006; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 17)
  - Notes and articles, 2005; Series 4 (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Proposals to change NCLB, 2006; Series 4 (Box 89, Folder 18)
  - Press list/contacts, undated; Series 4 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - NCLB reauthorization hearing summaries, undated; Series 4 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - NCTQ letters to districts and unions, undated; Series 4 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - NCLB, 2007-09; Series 4 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - CCCR Teacher Distribution Study in Ohio, 2008; Series 4 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - CCCR reports, 2001-07; Series 4 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Union report, 2008-09; Series 4 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Education standards, 2009; Series 4 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Civil Rights Report, 2009; Series 4 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Google settlement, 2009; Series 4 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Joyce report, 2009; Series 4 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Martin, Carmel, 2009; Series 4 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Passion of my Times flyer, Series 4 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Polis Charter School Bill, 2009; Series 4 (Box 91, Folder 7)